<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Sri's Portfolio</title><link>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/types/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Sri's Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:26:14 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/types/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gitlab Newcomer Bot</title><link>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/projects/gitlab-newcomer-bot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:26:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/projects/gitlab-newcomer-bot/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a greeter bot that we&amp;rsquo;re testing in GNOME to welcome first time contributors and put them into a nurture path. The idea is that contributors who putting their first issue or even their merge/pull request will be required to acknowledge the GNOME Code of Conduct and then provide some helpful links. For MRs, we will also need to set expectation that while their code contribution is valuable that there maybe reasons that they will be rejcted. This will help reduce churn. There are still challenges of course, but having this service will really help provide a more welcoming experience. The project will be tested on the GNOME engagement team before we start convincing other project maintainers to incorporate the bot in their issue/code contributions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ratatoskr MCP Server</title><link>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/projects/ratatoskr-mcp-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 20:39:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/projects/ratatoskr-mcp-server/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCP Server for GNOME integration, providing access to GNOME desktop information and system details via the Model Context Protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="key-points"&gt;Key Points&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore MCP tooling possibilities with the GNOME destop. Using DBus, the MCP server is able to query and set values. An LLM will be able to for instance know what wifi networks are available and be able to determine which is the safest one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the MCP server to start various sessions. For instance, the MCP server can set up the a desktop session to have everything ready to code a project. It could even change the lights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="impact"&gt;Impact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the viability of the GNOME in the AI world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hugin MCP Client</title><link>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/projects/hugin-mcp-client/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 20:39:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/projects/hugin-mcp-client/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MCP client is used as a way to test ratatoskr mcp server. Both
projects serve as a way to enable an AI PC idea to connect an LLM to
do useful tasks on a laptop or desktop. Hugin supports both a local LLM
and Claude. Optimizing the local LLM usecase will be priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="key-points"&gt;Key points&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a Linux based &amp;ldquo;AI PC&amp;rdquo; on the GNOME desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the MCP client as a way to test the MCP server to try doing tooling requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the viabilty of doing AI on the Linux platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="impact"&gt;Impact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show usefulness of an AI workflow on Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Containerized GNOME</title><link>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/projects/containerized-gnome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ramkrishna.me/projects/containerized-gnome/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is currently not active as GNOME OS still needs some work
that will make this more interesting. But this is a technology preview
to see if we can run GNOME in a container under kubernetes and be able
to support wide scaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="features"&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run GNOME OS in a container and deploy to thousands of instances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run applicatons in a GNOME OS containers as a &amp;lsquo;meta app container&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A extensions in a robust manner using openQA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to test all extensions based on a tag in GNOME Shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="technology-stack"&gt;Technology Stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podman + systemd support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://os.gnome.org"&gt;GNOME OS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;systemd-sysupdate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;systemd-homed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://buildstream.build/index.html"&gt;Buildstream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>